Daehwa Kim

407 South Craig Street, Pittsburgh, PA 15213 daehwak@andrew.cmu.edu • +1 415 937 4111 • https://daehwa.github.io

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research goal is creating naturalistic and intimate computing experience by exploring high-fidelity interface technologies. This interest can be applied for various domains, particularly wearable computing, mobile computing and extended reality environments. I presented several papers at ACM CHI and UIST and have been recognized with two Best Paper Honorable Mention awards at CHI.

EDUCATION

Ph.D. student, Carnegie Mellon University, School of Computer Science,

Human-Computer Interaction Institute

Sep 2022 – Current

Advised by Prof. Chris Harrison at Future Interfaces Group

M.Sc., KAIST, School of Computing

Mar 2019 – Feb 2021

- Advised by Prof. Geehyuk Lee at Human-Computer Interaction Lab
- Thesis: "OddEyeCam: Sensing Technique for Body-Centric Peephole Interaction Using WFoV RGB and NFoV Depth Cameras" (2020 Best Thesis Award)

B.S., UNIST, Electrical and Computer Engineering

Mar 2015 – Feb 2019

- Computer Science and Engineering (Major) and Electrical Engineering (Minor)
- Entered with top honors.
- Summer session program, UAL (University of the Arts London), London, UK

Jul 2018

PUBLICATIONS

- [1] Craig Shultz, <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Karan Ahuja, and Chris Harrison, "TriboTouch: Micro-Patterned Surfaces for Low Latency Touchscreens" in *Proceedings of the 2022 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*, New Orleans, LA, USA, Apr 2022. Best Paper Honorable Mention Award; Top 5%
- [2] <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Keunwoo Park, and Geehyuk Lee, "AtaTouch: Robust Finger Pinch Detection for a VR Controller Using RF Return Loss" in *Proceedings of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*, Yokohama, Japan. <u>Best Paper Honorable Mention Award</u>; Top 5%
- [3] <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Keunwoo Park, and Geehyuk Lee, "OddEyeCam: A Sensing Technique for Body-Centric Peephole Interaction Using WFoV RGB and NFoV Depth Cameras" in *Proceedings of the 33rd Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology*, Virtual Event, USA, Oct 2020.
- [4] Keunwoo Park, <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Seongkook Heo, and Geehyuk Lee, "MagTouch: Robust Finger Identification for a Smartwatch Using a Magnet Ring and a Built-in Magnetometer" in *Proceedings of the 2020 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*, Honolulu, Hawaii, USA, Apr 2020.

AWARDS & HONORS

Best Paper Honorable Mention Award, ACM CHI 2022

May 2022

 Craig Shultz, <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Karan Ahuja, and Chris Harrison, "TriboTouch: Micro-Patterned Surfaces for Low Latency Touchscreens" in *Proceedings of the 2022 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*, New Orleans, LA, USA, Apr 2022.

Best Paper Honorable Mention Award, ACM CHI 2021

May 2021

 <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Keunwoo Park, and Geehyuk Lee, "AtaTouch: Robust Finger Pinch Detection for a VR Controller Using RF Return Loss" in *Proceedings of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*, Yokohama, Japan.

Best Master's Thesis Award, KAIST School of Computing

Feb 2021

 Thesis: "OddEyeCam: Sensing Technique for Body-Centric Peephole Interaction Using WFoV RGB and NFoV Depth Cameras"

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Future Interfaces Group, Carnegie Mellon University

- Full-time Research Associate, Human-Computer Interaction Institute
- Sep 2021 Apr 2022
- Project: Exploring new touch input and human pose tracking technologies.

Advisor: Prof. Chris Harrison

HCI Lab, KAIST

	 Undergraduate Research Student, School of Computing Project: PCB design for a hand gesture sensing wristband. Advisor: Prof. Geehyuk Lee Focus: human-computer interaction, PCB design, physical prototyping 	Mar 2018 – Jun 2018
ACADEMIC	Reviewer	
SERVICE	 UIST '22, CHI '22 LBW, IMWUT '21, CHI '21 LBW 	
PROJECTS	Audio Hero	Sep 2019 – Dec 2019
	 Sound-based danger detection system using VGGish deep learning model Skills: Deep learning, Signal processing 	
	VRone	Sep 2018 – Dec 2018
	 3-dimensional force feedback in VR using a personal and commercial drone Skills: Unity C# programming, Android programming 	
	System Light 2.0 @ ETRI	Jan 2018 – Mar 2018
	 Smart Home project - Building IoT system for lights Skills: Computer network, Natural language processing 	
	VibCat	Oct 2017 – Dec 2017
	Vibration Categorization for Input & InteractionSkills: Machine learning, Android programming	
	Finger joystick interaction	Feb 2017 – Nov 2017
	 Interaction technique to support finger's directional input using capacitive imag of a smartwatch's touchscreen 	e
	Skills: Machine learning, Android programming	May 2017 Ivy 2017
	 Poem a moment ■ An android software that shows Yoon Dongju's poems on the wallpaper ■ Available on Google Play store (download 1000+) 	Mar 2017 – Jun 2017
	 Skills: Android programming 	
	TUIT Android Lecture	Jun 2016 – Sep 2016
	Android development lecture provided to TUIT university students Skiller Android programming. Object oriented programming.	
	 Skills: Android programming, Object-oriented programming Mr.Bill 	Jun 2016 – Jul 2016
	 Algorithm and system to provide optimal Dutch pay way Available on Google Play store (download 500+) Skills: Android programming Graph theory 	

• Skills: Android programming, Graph theory